Um, Martasa, I we have a question from a
viewer, uh, Desert Fox. Um, what do you
make of the Pizzagate allegations and
crimes uh, involving more occultish
practices?
>> Yeah, you know, it's funny. There are
some email some documents in the Epstein
releases which contain these very uh
extraordinary sort of allegations of
yeah occult practices and murder and uh
you know very extreme things and it's
very difficult to vet them per se
because you know these are allegations
where the FBI recorded and they talked
about as far as I've seen there was not
any followup where they verified in
granular detail but it seems like they
did take it seriously enough to report
and you do have to report everything
that the report to you, but they did
discuss it in a way we should not
immediately dismiss it. So, I don't
really know what to make of that. Um,
but you know what I would say is that uh
you know, I've had to update my own
priors a little bit about how I think
the world works in the last few years
working on these stories. uh because a
lot of things which you know not saying
that that everything is true that people
alleged but a lot of things which were
dismissed as conspiracies at one point
uh they did turn out to be validated by
information later on and now they're
just sort of uh you know accepted as
being true. So even the sex trafficking
that you know elite sex trafficking of
children that Epstein was involved in
that's what sounds like an insane you
know egregious morally unconscionable
allegation to make a few years ago and
yet now we know it's very true. who's
documented voluminously. So, you know, I
don't really disparrage anyone for
having suspicions or bring up anything
about uh any of these subjects anymore
because I think it's all worthy of
investigation and and looking into
because it seems like pretty much
anything is potentially uh people were
capable of at this point. The very very
few
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Speaking of which, um I'm glad this
story this question came up because if
he hadn't asked it, I would have.
Reynolds reps asking uh what what do you
think of people saying that the bigger
story is that Epste was a money
launderer for intelligence agencies as
his main role?
>> Well, you know, it's very interesting.
We did a story about this at drop site
based on Epstein's, you know, longer
history. It was sort of almost a
rebuttal to the New York Times story
about how was uh he made his money. It
just happened to be timed in the same
way. But, you know, I think that that
that is true. That's but that was one
aspect of who Epstein was. I think that
he actually got his start as a money
launderer for intelligence uh uh
operations and he had he got his start
in the world of an episode known as Iran
Contra in the 1980s and he [snorts] was
very close to ti people tied to Iran
Contra uh Adnan Kosoji Douglas Lee John
Stanley Ping there many many other
individuals you can read about in their
story um and Iran Contra was a episode
where you not to go over in great detail
people will probably know a lot about it
but uh you know money was generated for
these black budgets, you know, off off
the books budget. That was the purpose.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. That was perfect. Exactly. So, you
need money which you could use for
things that you don't want the public to
know about and you don't want to be
subject to, you know, congressional or a
presidential oversight or whatever. Uh
you need people who are good at
laundering money and hiding money and
cleaning money. And he was someone who
was very good at that. And that became
his sort of uh you know his killer in
his his sort of key competency that he
had. as time group went on and he became
a very powerful person. I think that he
expanded his range. He was someone who
was this connector this uh individual
who was facilitating the activities of
powerful powerful people around the
world uh including moneyaundering and
beyond that as well too and I will say
one thing very quickly as well too we
haven't touched on the issue of uh the
the blackmail issue. You know, I think
that almost the question is almost a
moot point in some ways because people
keep raising the bar in the sense of
well there is there a photo of him and
standing behind the camera filming Bill
Clinton and you know confronting him
with a camera with a video and
threatening him to you know raise taxes
or something like that this is going to
happen. I think it's actually not even
necessary for that discourse of sort of
blackmail to take place because what we
do know is that he knew about the
activities that these powerful people
were doing and was facilitating them uh
for a very very long period of time and
he had privileged knowledge about things
that they didn't want to be public that
by its nature gives you leverage over
people you know inherently regardless of
when you course them thereafter or not
it does influence your relationship with
them so I think that you know he was
somebody who was in a politically
privileged role And I do hope we find
more granular information about this.
But uh yeah, I think he was somebody
who, you know, he he played many many
different roles and all of them were uh
you know, very consequential.
>> Rasa, in the time that we have left, um
are we going to see the other half of
the of the files? And uh and if if so,
what do you what would you like to find
in those?
>> You know, uh I hope so. Uh it's
interesting because they were quite
adamant it seemed after this release
that to describe it as the final release
and you know try to say this is the end
of the story and so
>> we heard that before though.
>> Yeah
>> exactly. Yeah. So I think there'll be a
fight and I know that Ro Kana and Thomas
Massie have insisted upon disclosure of
the final 3 million of the files and I
do find the excuses that they raised for
not releasing them privacy and so forth
were not very compelling because a lot
of private things were accidentally
released in this disclosure and so
forth. So I don't really you know buy
that per se but uh you know I hope we do
see and I hope that uh you know it's
released in a way which is uh a bit more
responsible first of all because I think
they released it was a disastrous uh
Epstein file releases so far
deliberately almost seen confusion
chaotic uh disorganized we're trying to
do our best to reorganize the files for
public uh analysis we we have a tool
called Jmail we're working on with some
researchers which restructures there's
all the emails and the image of a Google
inbox of Epstein so people can go
through chronologically and kind of see
when things fit together which you can
extract a lot more meaning from but but
you know I hope that uh if there is more
releases that they do release in a way
which allow people to actually uh view
it in a way which uh we can glean
information of more
>> last question before we let you go um is
the uh hazard way that the documents
have been released and you know and and
the huge mistakes for example the
unredacted naked photos of uh underage
uh girls. Um is that a feature or is it
a bug? Do you think it's just the sort
of haphazard nature nature of this
administration which didn't hire enough
people enough professional people to
handle this? Or is this an oldfashioned
document dump where we dump everything
on journalists and they just can't
handle it and process it on time and
then they hope that the uh public
interest moves on.
>> Oh well, if people remember they did it
on Friday afternoon. So Friday
afternoon. Yeah. The timing. Exactly. To
try to specifically uh you know dull the
impact of it and you know I would say
that in the age of you know you know you
can make an AI app to do something in
like half an hour now to arrange things
in a way which is accessible. I can only
imagine that this was intentional
because you know if we at drop site can
rearrange it with researchers in a more
digestible format. you were like eight
people a drop site and a few
researchers. Uh the the federal
government, the Department of Justice of
course can release this in a digestible
manner. I think they're trying not to.
>> Yeah, they have more money than God if
they want. Um thank you so much Martaza
Hussein for joining us. Hope you'll come
back. Um he's the national security and
foreign affairs correspondent at
Dropsite News and I would say an expert
on the Epstein files. So drop
dropsightnews.com.
If you haven't been, check it out. I'm
there every day.
Go check it out. Thanks so much.
>> Thank you, Mortaza.
>> Have a great day.
>> Thank you. Outstanding.
>> You know, Drop Site News,
this is what investigative journalism is
supposed to be, right? This is what the
the the Post, the Times, the Journal,
the LA Times, what they used to do,
>> right?
>> And and by the way, effective today,
there was a massive layoff at the
Washington Post.
>> It's happening right now
>> as we're speaking. I don't even know
still around.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. But drop site news, this is the
way journalism is supposed to be
>> for sure. Um and I look I I totally
agree with Martaza like the you know
with the a with AI
>> um you know you and I could process this
stuff. Um Oh yeah. You know I mean it's
not hard.
>> That's right. It's not hard. You're
[music] exactly right.